<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.theyoungrossco.netgrip</id>
  <name>NetGrip</name>
  <summary>Drag-and-drop network interface management</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>
      NetGrip shows your machine's network interfaces as boxes on a canvas:
      every IP configuration, VLAN and bond is its own box, joined to its
      interface by a line. Drag an IP configuration to another NIC to move
      it, drag two NICs together to create a bond, right-click to add VLANs
      or change bonding modes.
    </p>
    <p>
      It manages the local machine or any remote Linux host reachable over
      SSH, and always shows the exact iproute2 commands it will run before
      applying anything.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.theyoungrossco.netgrip.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/theyoungrossco/netgrip</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/theyoungrossco/netgrip/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/theyoungrossco/netgrip</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <binary>netgrip</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.4.2" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>A packaging fix for the Windows build: the running app's window and
        taskbar icon showed a generic network glyph because the frozen app
        wasn't bundling the NetGrip monogram SVG. The monogram now ships, so it
        appears correctly. Other platforms and the installer icon are
        unaffected.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.1" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>A maintenance release between milestones. Privileged actions on a
        remote host that requires a sudo password now prompt for it once, cached
        for the session, and run via sudo -S with the password sent only over the
        SSH channel's stdin — so a password-sudo box is manageable from a client
        without local sudo, such as Windows. A runtime-only Debian/Proxmox host
        with classic ifupdown can install ifupdown2 in one click, turning it into
        a backend Save can write through. And the canvas exports to a vector SVG
        (content-sized) or a US Letter PDF via File, Export diagram.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>Docker visibility, read-only. A docker bridge is labelled by its
        network name, and each running container is drawn as a single box on the
        networks it joins, showing its image, its IP per network and its compose
        project/service; the container's host-side veth is folded into that box.
        Published ports draw as dashed connectors to the host address they bind
        to, and each container's outbound default route as a dotted line to the
        uplink, both keyed in the legend and toggleable from the View menu.
        Read best-effort via docker inspect, so a host without docker is
        unaffected; docker-owned links are read-only.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-06-21">
      <description>
        <p>Persistence and clarity. Changes can now Save across reboots through
        the host's own backend (netplan, systemd-networkd, NetworkManager or
        ifupdown), with Try (apply then auto-revert) and Apply alongside it.
        Addresses are grouped per protocol into IPv4/IPv6 boxes carrying their
        gateway and DNS; a System DNS box shows where each resolver comes from.
        Adds a View menu, a legend overlay, wired/wireless glyphs, veth pairing,
        vlan-aware bridge tags, draft VLANs, Windows as an SSH client, and
        one-command installers for Linux and Windows.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release: canvas view, IP config move/clone by drag,
        bonds and VLANs, SSH remote hosts, demo mode.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
